Welcome to Using the style book.<br />Learning Outcomes. Learn best practices
for using the style book, understand the<br />difference between global styles and the
style book, how they work together to<br />learn how to add customization and
styling before setting up your website.<br />If you have not viewed styling your site
with global styles, please do so to get<br />a better understanding of global styles.
Learn WordPress videos are found on<br />YouTube under WordPress, the URL link is
below also.
To find the style book, we're going to<br />start in our dashboard. And we will
scroll down the menu to appearance. We<br />will go over to the editor and click on
that to open that up. Under the design<br />menu, you'll see the styles. We'll click
on that. And we've opened up a kind of<br />mini menu that shows WordPress default,
it has comes with eight different style<br />variations. So we can kind of stop here
and I'm going to show you a couple of<br />different ways to do the same thing. So
this is going to be one way of choosing<br />a different style combination for your
theme. And there's different colors and<br />fonts. So this is the default page that
comes with the theme. And this is kind<br />of the blog home template. Okay. So
there's a bunch of kind of different<br />blocks that they used. And what we can
do is we can pick and click on the<br />different color variations to see how
they would look. And if you notice that<br />the font will change also, as we go
through the different colors. But we're<br />just going to stick with the default for
right now because I want to show you<br />some other things on this page. Up here
at the top, there is an eye icon. And<br />when you hover over it says the style
book and then there's a pencil icon that<br />says Edit styles. So, if we click on the
style book icon, the eye, what comes up<br />is the headings, paragraphs, images, all
the core blocks that are being used. And<br />again, we can take and click on our
different style variations, to see what<br />looks good with the different blocks.
The other feature that is good to point<br />out is that down here is last modified
so there's actually a revisions that we<br />can click on. And it opens up our page.
And it shows the style revisions. And it<br />shows when I did the revision, and when
I click on it on the day, it'll kind of<br />give me a overview of what was changed
and updated, which is kind of cool.<br />Okay. And there's other ways to get to
this also. So let's go back up here and<br />we'll go into the edit styles.
So this will be the main page that<br />people usually go to. And you'll notice
that the Styles menu on the right opened<br />up automatically, if it doesn't open up
automatically, just come over to the<br />halfmoon. And click on that to open it.
And if you've watched the global styles<br />video, you already know what these
things can do. Okay. So again, here is<br />our eye icon. Here is our clock icon
that shows the revision. So here's the<br />other way to get to it. So again, we
have the blog, home template as kind of<br />our default page, or browse styles just
like in that first section. And we can<br />do the same thing, we can look at the
page and we can try the different color<br />variations out and then go to the style
book. And what that does is it provides<br />those, the theme core blocks, but this
time in a little bit easier to manage<br />view because it has tabs and they've put
the different blocks into the different<br />tabs. So that's a little bit easier. So
all the media's together, design<br />features buttons, groups, such as
widgets are those things that you might<br />have like a list with links a calendar
again list posts list page list, your<br />social media icons is all kind of a
widget, it's all together. And then our<br />theme blocks will be together too. So
again, I can go into my style<br />variations, and I can see how the
different colors are going to look<br />within these areas. So it's kind of
really cool. The media doesn't have<br />much, the buttons is probably the bigger
one, because of the fact that the button<br />is going to have a different color in in
some of them have different shapes to,<br />to kind of find the best one that fits
with you. Okay, so the other thing that<br />you can do is when you're going through,
and this is where the global styles and<br />styles kind of work together.
So if we're doing kind of our blocks,<br />and I, I like all the other colors, but
I, I want to do a little pop, you know,<br />I like the basic, if we look at the
colors of this the palette, I like the<br />grays and blacks, but I want to pop a
color for my button right in the style<br />book under the Design tab, you can also
customize your your buttons and kind of<br />see a preview. If we click on the block,
it will open up the styling tools for<br />this. So we can go in and change the
background color. And we'll go with this<br />light brown. And then we'll change the
text to a black. And we can also change<br />the appearance and make it a medium
text. And we can also change the font.<br />And that doesn't look good. So let's go
back to our original. Well, we can use<br />that we can use the system sans one. So
there's different ways that we can add<br />things and kind of preview them over
here. So I'm going to hit save, and save<br />again. And then when I go to my front
end and refresh my page, you'll see that<br />I have the styles done.
We are going to go over to the text and<br />look at the quote block. Now most of our
styling we want to do in the global<br />styles, but sometimes there's a special
block that might need some, just a<br />special little something. So we're going
to click on that open up the block, and<br />we're going to add in a background
color. So we can change that. Okay, we<br />can also change the font and we'll do
that. And then we can hit Save. And<br />we'll hit Save again. And now when we go
in when we tick off our style block, we<br />can see that in our template that we can
preview this here and then when we go to<br />our front end and refresh our page, and
we'll scroll down we can see how it<br />looks there.
Check out more<br />lessons@learn.wordpress.org or our
YouTube channel at WordPress. Thank you